THE FIFTH WAVE
Translation. Review by Angel.
Help me?
THE FIFTH WAVE
Is somebody there?
I am hurt.
Please?
I am bleeding.
Help me?
Drop your weapon.
You drop yours first.
Drop it!
Okay.
Your turn.
Let me see your other hand.
If I move this hand, I am afraid
my stomach will fall out.
I need to see your other hand.
- What is in your hand?
- Nothing.
Drop your weapon.
What is in your hand?
I miss the Cassie I was.
Hey.
A totally normal
high school girl.
- Hey! How are you doing?
- Hi! Good.
- Cheers.
- Thank you. Cheers.
I wonder what that Cassie
would think of me now.
The Cassie who kills.
You know, he was
supposed to be here.
Who?
Why are the hot ones
always so unreliable?
What would I even say to him?
I do not know him,
and he does not even know me.
You are a girl. He is a boy.
- Your parts go together.
- Do not.
God!
- Okay, Liz.
- What?
I am going to see you Monday.
I have to go home.
Skedaddle.
Okay.
- I love you.
- Bye!
- Text me when you are home.
Okay.
Hey?
Hey!
Nice phone case.
What? Do you have
something against pink?
No! No. I totally like it.
I am just kidding.
This is actually
my sister's phone.
I dropped her off at a sleepover,
and she took mine by mistake.
Mine is much cooler.
It is the Spider-Man.
Polka dots.
That is she.
Hey.
Yeah, yeah, I have it.
No! No I have not looked
at your text messages.
Nice phone case!
Right.
I am the Captain Lochner,
this is Sergeant Nicolai.
- Hello.
- How do you do?
I am sorry. No more coffee.
Miss Gray, do you
know this gentleman?
Sing me a song.
A song?
Okay, close your eyes.
Bones sinking like stones.
All we fought it.
I did not know it then,
but that was the last
normal day of my life.
All of us are done.
When you are in high school, just about
everything feels like the end of the world.
Can you believe what happened?
No.
An early curfew,
a final exam...
- Hey, Ben!
- Stop it.
Soccer practice.
Sullivan. What are
we doing out here?
Why not just tell her where
you are going to kick it?
Come on, let us go.
Hey, check it out.
Look at this. It is so freaky.
- Watch!
- I cannot see anything.
My God! Altschuler.
That is it. You are done.
Off the field.
No! However, look!
It is weird.
Off! Goodbye. Adios.
- What is going on?
- Let us go! Hustle up!
Give me your phone.
Mine does not work!
- It very just stopped.
- All right, Perkins.
Turns out, what we thought
was the end of the world.
Was not.
What? Did someone famous
die or something?
It appears to be metallic
and, of a considerable size.
Across the world, social media has
been awash with panic and speculation,
as these images
spread like wildfire.
The president has authorized NASA to
attempt communication with the object.
That is now circling
our planet.
And, is currently over the United
States, moving west over Ohio.
My God! It is right over us.
I want to see!
- Hey!
- No! Sammy waits.
Sammy waits!
- You can see it!
- Come here!
Look up there, honey.
- What is that?
- I have no idea.
There were no messages from our galactic
party crashers during the first 10 days.
But, pretty soon,
they had a name.
We called them: "The Others."
Are the Wilsons leaving, too?
They say they do not feel safe
so close to the city.
Okay.
Is this everyone?
Guess, who is sitting
right behind me.
Well, okay.
Everybody look at the
equation on the board.
I will tell him you are available
for sex in the end of world.
Who can give me the
derivative of X?
Anybody?
Anyone?
What...?
I am sure this is
just a power outage.
My phone is not working.
What is going on?
Over here!
What is on Earth?
My goodness! What is going on?
Look at up!
Back up! Back up!
"The Others" hit us with an electromagnetic
pulse that killed all the power on the planet.
No more engines.
No more electricity.
No more running water.
No more everything,
we took for granted.
That was the last time
I saw Ben Parish.
I guess, he is dead now.
Like everyone else
in that room.
Here, Sam. Grab me another
one, okay! Thank you!
That was the first Wave.
At the time, we
thought that was it.
Then, the second Wave hit us.
Come on! Sammy. It
is an earthquake!
Cassie! Watch out!
Cassie! Go on!
Go! Go! Wait!
Cassie!
It is okay. It is okay.
Just keep your
head down, okay!
What is that noise?
Sammy, run!
- Go!
- Cassie!
Go on!
Cassie!
Go.
- Cassie! Hurry up!
- I am fine!
- Go, Sammy! Go!
- Cassie!
Come here. Hold on to me.
Cassie!
In Ohio, we only had the lake
to worry about.
But, by the ocean,
I can only imagine.
Every coastal city,
every island,
It was gone.
There are over 300 billion
birds in the world.
That is 75 birds
for every person.
Mom said the avian flu was already one
of the world's deadliest viruses.
In the third Wave, "The
Others" modified it.
They made it unstoppable.
And, the birds spread
across of the planet.
Line A. Line A is for those who
have already been assessed.
If you are waiting to be assessed,
then proceed to Line B.
No pedal pulse, no
brachial, nothing.
Sit down, sir. Thank you!
Just head straight on back.
I am not happy over here.
I feel fine!
I should be on the area
that is not quarantined!
Hey, Liz!
- Hey.
- Your mom said you were here.
- Cassie! Cassie!
- Mom?
What are you...?
She is in quarantined.
- It is okay. I did not even touch her.
- It is not okay. You cannot be here.
I am sorry.
Sweetheart, I need you to go
home and look after Sammy, okay!
However, Mom, I want to
help you here.
Can you get her
out of here now?
- Mom!
- It is okay. Just go.
Miss, you have to leave.
Let us go.
- Quarantine six.
- In six.
Some people were
immune to the virus.
And, a few people got sick
and, somehow recovered.
But, most people did not.
MOMMY
Hey.
You cannot wear those shoes.
Why do not they just
get over with it?
What do they want?
I think a better question is:
"What do they need?"
They have been very
careful so far.
Not to damage it any more
than absolutely necessary.
What is damage?
The Earth!
I think that is why
they are here, Cassie.
They need the Earth.
However, not us.
No! Not us.
Do you ready to walk
for a while, Sammy?
Yeah.
Okay.
Dad, how far is it
to the refugee camp?
Just a few miles. We should
be there by nightfall.
- Dad, look! Is this it?
- Yeah, buddy. I think so.
Hey! Welcome!
Thanks. Hi.
The name is Hutch field.
Hi! See you.
Let me show you
around the place.
The latrines are there
off to the left.
The farm is out that way.
Did you get the fresh water?
Yeah! Not too bad!
How many people
are there in here?
I do not know how
many we are now.
Three hundred and five,
something like that.
Dining hall is over here.
When is the last time
you had a hot meal?
Good! Maybe you can
walk me through it.
Here, we draw a purple hat.
Can we get some
water over here?
- Dad.
- This is a Colt 45.
Okay!
This button changes
out the clip.
That is loaded.
All right? Safety on.
Safety off.
Listen to me.
You are going to carry this
with you at all times.
You are not going to tell
anybody you have it.
And you are only going to use it if
it is life or death. Do you get it?
I thought we were safe here.
Pumpkin, there is
nothing safe anymore.
Here, you want to put
it in the basket.
Okay.
- Here. Take this one.
- Okay.
You got to get the weeds.
What is that?
Sammy, come here.
- What is that?
- I do not know. Come on!
Asher, come on!
Mommy?
Dad?
CAMP CUYAHOGA - WELCOME.
What is that?
- Do you see Dad?
- Dad?
- Cassie?
- Hey, Dad.
Hey.
- What is going on?
- Guys take it easy.
I thought the cars
did not work.
SCHOOL BUS
I am Colonel Vosch
of the US Army.
My men and I are from the
Wright-Patterson Air Force Base.
We are here to help.
It is in time.
We let us get people
out of here.
- Heck, yeah!
- Thank you.
Yes!
USA!
We should be ready to go at a
moment is notice. All right!
You stay with your
sister, Sammy.
- Come on!
- You can go right on the bus.
Adults, please move to the
mess hall for a briefing.
Children, please move
to the buses for transport.
We are right behind you.
Be good!
Adults, please move to the
mess hall for a briefing.
Do you think they have electricity?
If the trucks are working.
I do not know. Why, do you
still have a phone?
Yeah.
- You have a charger.
- Of course, yeah.
- Sir, sir.
- Yeah?
My orders are to get
just the kids onto the bus.
Well, those might be your
orders, but they are my kids.
- Yeah.
- We are going to stay together.
- We will wait for another bus.
- It is all right, Private.
I get this.
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you.
Look! You are welcome to keep
them here with you if want.
But, if they were my kids,
I would get them in that bus.
Why?
We have reason to believe there is
an imminent threat to this location.
We are trying to get everyone
to safety as quickly as we can,
and this is the only working
transport we have got.
We are taking shifts
based on need.
Kids first, then we come back
for the rest of you.
Well! How safe is it
at Wright-Patterson?
Safest place there
is right now.
In addition, the buses will
just come right back?
Dad? No!
We drop them off,
come right back.
As if I said, it is your call.
Just because some man in uniform
tries to tell us what to do...
does not mean, we actually
have to follow his orders.
Okay! I want you on
this one. All right?
- I will be right behind you.
- We cannot split up.
Moreover, we are going to have dinner
tonight. We are going to the same place.
- Dad! No!
- Cassie.
It is the Army, okay. This is our Army.
It is fine. It is going to be okay.
Do not leave me alone.
I love you.
Take care of your brother.
All right? Come here.
I want you to listen
to your sister. All right?
- Okay.
- She is in charge.
- Okay?
- Dad!
Go ahead.
I will be there
before you know it.
Here, ahead to
the back, Sammy.
All right.
All right!
- Give me your backpack.
- Bear!
- What?
- Cassie, I forgot Bear!
- Cassie.
- What? Sammy, what?
- I forgot Bear! I need to get him!
- Sammy stops. Sit down.
- What is up?
- I cannot. I cannot go without him.
Please!
All right! All right! All right!
All right! I will get him, okay?
Just stay here. All right?
- I will be right back.
- Do you promise?
Yeah! I will be right back.
I promise you.
Right, no, I think
you are right.
Just grab whatever you can get
up in a box and carry it.
This way. Down to the mess hall.
In the mess hall now, please.
Come on! Sammy.
Bear. Bear. Bear. Bear.
Bear. Bear. Bear.
God! Sammy?
Hey! Wait!
Stop!
Sammy!
Cassie! Wait please! Stop!
Sammy! No! Sammy Waits!
Sammy!
Cassie! Come on.
Cassie!
Sammy!
No!
Cassie, no! No!
Shit!
Can I have your
attention, please?
If you will all
just quiet down.
We believe the fourth
Wave has begun.
"The Others" came
down off their ship.
They are moving among us.
Apparently, they have the
ability to inhabit human hosts,
and control their actions.
- They look like humans.
- That is correct.
Where are they?
They could be anywhere.
What we do know is: They have
snipers in these woods,
and they are
targeting survivors.
We have Intel that suggest...
Some of them could be right
here in this camp.
What? Are you saying that
some of us are "The Others"?
Please! There is a lot,
we still do not know.
We can detect
them in children.
Unfortunately, the screening procedure
for adults is a bit more complicated.
What about our kids?
Yeah! What about our kids?
I know. I know you all want to
get back to your families.
Unfortunately, we are going to have to
move you all to a secure holding facility.
So, they can run some
screening protocols.
Folks, please?
You need to understand, there is no way
to differentiate us from "The Others".
Without a comprehensive
screening process.
The sooner we can get
you screened.
The sooner you can get back
to your families.
This is bullshit!
I am not a "The Others", okay.
I am not going anywhere.
Sir, no one is saying
that you are "The Others".
This is the reality
of our situation.
Now, you just calm down.
Please, just calm down.
Let me out of here.
Get out of my way. Watch out!
- Hold on, sir.
- Wait.
- Back up, now.
- Stop right there.
- Sir, drops your weapon.
- Step aside, now.
- Drew, no!
You cannot keep me in here!
- Everybody, just calm down!
- Let me out now!
Lower the weapon, now.
- I want to see my kids!
- Put it down!
Let me out of here!
No! Drew, stop!
Stay down!
Run!
No! No! No!
Hey, Dad?
Daddy?
I am sorry!
I need my Dad.
God!
Security teams, clear zones
three and four.
Support team members,
meet arrivals on the tarmac.
Stand in the red circle. Wait
for your number to be called.
Number one-two-seven.
Stand in the red circle. Wait
for your number to be called.
Two-nine-five.
Here.
Number seven-three.
Seven-three.
Number seven-four.
Number one-three-zero.
One-nine-four.
One-three-zero.
What is your name?
Ben Parish.
They called me "Zombie"
in quarantine.
Any family not know
that you be dead?
No.
My sister died in the quakes.
Mom and Dad killed
by the Virus.
However, it did not
kill you, did it?
Not quite.
Where from did the
Nickname comes?
You fought it off.
Yeah, lucky me.
Is this your sister's?
Yeah.
Well, lucky you.
You get to help
avenge her death.
This puts out a signal
that we can track.
You kids are the most
important thing right now.
We need every one of you
to help us fight "The Others".
This is not summer camp,
Zombie! You are a soldier now.
Therefore, we do not want
to lose you. Stand up.
Turn around.
Take a deep breath.
Are you all right?
How are we supposed to fight "The Others?"
If we do not even know, what are they?
Actually, we do.
Do you want to see one?
Do not worry. He will not
be able to see us.
I know. It is
impossible to tell.
Look through here.
Look!
It is its true form.
"The Others" infest real humans
like some sort of parasite.
Take over their
minds, their bodies.
Drugs, radiation,
surgery, nothing works.
The only way to kill them
is to kill the host.
He is already dead.
You just need to destroy
the thing inside him.
The thing that did this.
Push the button.
Look again!
Look!
If you are going to
be on my squad.
I need to know that you will
do to whatever it takes.
Welcome to the fight.
Here is how you kill
off a species.
First, you take out the easy
ones, the weak, the exposed.
Kill them as efficiently
as possible.
It was the first
of three Waves.
But, even if you bomb a bug of the house,
there is always a few cockroaches left.
Now, we are like
those cockroaches.
And "The Others" are
picking us.
One by one.
And because "The
Others" look like us.
We cannot trust anyone.
Eighty miles to
Wright-Patterson.
I am coming, Sammy.
I promise you.
How do you rid the
world of humans?
Help me!
First, you rid the humans
of their humanity.
WRIGHT-PATTERSON AF9 - 46 ML.
Shit!
Shit! Shit!
God!
Sammy.
All right! All right!
God!
I am sorry, Sammy.
When I was a child,
I spoke as a child.
I thought and I
reasoned as a child.
When I became a man.
I put away the
things childish.
Those words never meant more
to me than they do right now,
looking at all of you.
Our hope, our future.
The best and brightest vision of who
we are and what for we are fighting.
Our intelligence tells us "The Others" is
readying themselves for a final attack.
The fifth Wave.
What form it will
take, we do not know.
If they are successful.
There will be no more Wave.
No more conflicts.
Humanity as we know, it will be
wiped from the face of the Earth.
Now.
I am going to tell you
some things I know.
This is our world.
It is our home.
They will not overrun it.
They will not possess it.
So, with whatever the
time that we have left.
You will learn to think, speak, and
move, fight like the soldiers you are.
Look out! A raid!
Go!
Fire!
Let the weight of our loss
to be fuel for you.
Let the weight of our
dead embolden you.
On your right! On your right!
Let the weight of our hope
drive you to victory.
Can you do that?
All right! Hold on!
Soldiers, can you do that?
Sir, yes, sir!
Zombie!
- Get down! Do not move!
- It is a booby trap!
Can you do that?
Sir, yes, sir!
Good!
Come on!
Where is my gun?
Where is it?
I know, you are awake.
Cassie?
How the hell, do you
know my name?
Your driver's license.
I am Evan.
Evan Walker.
Where am I?
You were bleeding on the highway. I
brought you back here to my house.
Where is my gun?
All right! When you found me on the
highway, I had my gun. Where is it?
I did not see any gun.
What did you do?
Your leg, Cassie.
- Do not touch me! Do not touch me!
- Your leg.
Jesus!
God!
Put your leg.
- This is going to hurt.
- Just do it. Just do it.
God!
Okay.
How long have I been here?
About a week.
God!
How far is Wright-Patterson
from here?
The military base?
About sixty miles.
Why?
Jesus!
Hey. It is okay.
- You are safe here.
- No.
I am not safe
anywhere anymore.
Why did you want to know how
close Wright-Patterson was?
It is my brother.
The Army took him
to there, so I...
I need to get him back.
What?
You should eat.
You got to get your
strength back.
Why would you bring me here?
What do you want?
My family.
I could not save them.
However, I could save you.
The way everything has happened, I
guess it just makes me feel more...
Human.
In addition, you
need help with that.
Feeling human.
Do not you?
Maybe.
- You are cheating.
- I am not cheating.
Do not you tell him my card?
Do you hear me Oompa?
I have been getting lucky, and,
this is not my first time playing.
By the way, I heard the new person coming
in got kicked out of their last squad.
- For what?
- Disciplinary issues.
Is that true boss?
That is what they say.
What is his name?
The name is Ringer.
In addition, he is a she.
Bunk is over there.
Did you ever do karate before?
No.
Sure looks like you did.
Are you Zombie?
Yeah.
I was the leader
of my last squad.
No doubt.
So, the person I replace
went Section eight. Why?
Does it matter?
I heard it is because
this squad is so bad.
He was afraid you had get him
killed when the fifth Wave hits.
It is your squad, too, now.
Hey!
Keep staring at my ass,
and I will rip
your throats out.
Let us be clear.
I am not taking orders from you. I am
not going to die with you geniuses.
Good to know.
If anyone in this barrack
touches me, I will kill them.
You got it.
Anything else?
I like to play chess.
Do you play?
No, actually.
But, if you want to play
some strip poker later on...
Shit!
And no demeaning,
sexist remarks.
She is cool.
Quiet!
You had my gun the whole time!
Why did you lie?
I was afraid you
would shoot me.
All I knew, you were
a "The Others".
Yeah, well...
Was he one? Out there!
Yeah.
The woods are full of them.
They are using those drones
to hunt down survivors.
He looked so human.
God! I have to get Sam.
Cassie.
Rallying points,
places like Wright-Patterson.
They are obvious targets.
Do you think that Sammy
is already dead?
I am sorry, Cassie.
You are wrong, Evan.
All right! He is alive.
He is alive, and I am
going to go get him.
Cassie?
I am going with you.
You are not going to make it
very far on your own.
Do you know what?
Screw you, Evan.
- I do not need you. I do not need anyone.
- Cassie! Come on!
- If you go, I will just follow you.
- Actually, no.
If I need someone
to carve a cane for me.
You cannot stop me.
How are you going to stop me?
I do not know. Maybe
I will shoot you!
Like you shot that person
with the crucifix!
Do you read my journal?
- I did not think you were going to live.
- Do not touch me!
I am sorry.
I will get you there.
I cannot promise that you will
find, but I will get you there.
We leave in the morning.
This is a waste of time.
Go ahead and try it again.
Those kids are going to be dead
before their boots hit the ground.
Especially with you
as squad leader.
You do not know
anything about me.
Let me guess.
You did well in school,
had a bunch of friends.
You probably played football.
You might have even
been team captain.
Life was easy.
And then, all of a
sudden, it was not.
No more games to win.
No one to get weak-kneed
for this pretty smile.
You were not ready for
the end of world.
In addition, were you?
I know how to survive.
In addition, I was doing fine
out there on my own.
Until they forced me onto
their stupid school bus.
They were rescuing us.
We were not rescued,
dumb-ass. We were drafted.
Good! Good!
Try it again.
How about this?
I take you down.
You teach us how to shoot.
In addition, when you do not.
I stop asking you.
Deal.
Cute necklace.
Girlfriend or sister?
Sister.
You are too sentimental.
Can you teach me that thing? Where
you took the gun out of my hand.
Let us just leave any
potential disarming to me.
No!
No! I need to be ready.
Cassie, it is okay.
You do not have to be
tough all the time.
Do not do that.
I am not tough, okay!
I promised Sammy that I would be
there for him no matter what.
I made that promise to him.
Okay.
Give me your gun.
Get up.
Point it at my chest.
Okay! Grab the barrel of
the gun with your hand left,
and with your hand right,
snap my hand away.
You got it.
You are not going to hurt me.
All right!
Like that, but stronger.
Good!
Now at the end, you will grab my
wrist and pull it toward you.
- Like this?
- Yeah.
Good job.
Well, thanks.
Can I have...?
Okay! Do not be so
scared of your weapon.
You got to think that the gun
is a part of you.
The gun is not firing,
you are firing.
Try it again.
Well! That was not terrible.
Zombie, the Colonel
wants to see you, now.
It could be. It seems
like a good target.
I will be right back.
- Lieutenant?
- Yes, sir.
Simultaneous attacks on the
last of our metropolitan areas.
A full-on invasion.
This is it.
The fifth Wave.
Was it started?
Yeah.
Here, I want to
show you something.
These employ the same technology as
the detector viewer the medical.
We have improved it.
We made it mobile.
The idea is to allow
our soldiers in the field...
Instantly, differentiate
between friend and foe.
You look at the enemy through this,
and it lights them up green.
We can see them before them
know they have been seen.
We take back the advantage.
The only thing left to do now is
test the optics in live conditions.
This is why tomorrow at 2100,
I am sending four squads into
battle equipped with these helmets.
Your squad will be
among those four.
Yes, sir.
Make me proud, son.
Bring that squad
back in one piece.
Yes, sir.
Evan?
- Good morning!
Whom do we have here?
This is Lizbeth.
She is my best friend.
She looks like she is funny.
Yeah. Actually, you
know, she was...
She was funny.
- And this person.
- He is nobody.
This must be Ben Parish.
God!
I really wish you had not
read my journal.
It is embarrassing.
Is that your family?
Yeah.
In addition, that must be Sam.
I cannot wait to meet him.
- We should probably get moving.
- Yeah.
All right! This way.
How do you know
without a compass?
Do you have a compass?
No. However...
You know, I can make one out
of a pin and a glass of water.
Would not peg you
that is a Girl Scout.
What would you peg me?
A cheerleader?
You said it, not me.
I have never been a huge fan
of the outdoors.
Too many bugs.
You live on a farm.
Accident of birth.
I had a scholarship
to Kent State.
Mechanical engineering.
You thought I was some hick.
You said it, not me.
Zombie! Are they really
sending us to fight?
Yeah.
I am scared.
It is okay.
Just go to sleep. All right!
What was your name before?
Ben.
What was yours?
Sam.
However, my sister
called me Sammy.
When I could not sleep.
She would sing to me.
"Bones sinking like stones."
"All that we fought."
"Homes, places that
we have grown."
"All of us are done."
Could you people,
please, shut up?
"We live in a
beautiful world."
"Yeah, we do, yeah, we do."
"We live in a
beautiful world."
Hey. Let me help you.
Yeah, sure.
- Looks better.
- Yeah.
- Let me do this.
- All right.
- Do you get scissors?
- Yeah.
I got it.
- I should probably cover our stuff.
- Evan.
Thank you.
- Squad fifty-three?
- Present and accounted.
All right!
Strap in. Takeoff.
Where is Nugget?
Food poisoning.
Zombie?
Let me out of here!
Copy that. Tango 3
dropping down 1,000.
Did you clear of your orders?
Infiltrate enemy hornet's nest,
verify enemy and terminate.
Remember, "The Others" light
up green in your visors.
At mission was complete,
signal us for extraction.
We will take you to home.
Holy shit! It is working. You people,
I got two of them straight ahead.
In addition, I heard this.
I got you. You motherfuck!
I peed. I definitely peed.
Get inside!
Return fire!
Coming this way!
- They are over here, too!
- Run for the alley!
Go! Go! Go! Go!
- Teacup goes! Go!
- Go! Run!
Move!
Go! Go!
Contact!
Stay low!
Get to the bus.
Go!
Where is Teacup?
- Where is Teacup? We lost Teacup.
- I am here!
You do not do that! Do not
scare me like that!
Oompa has been shot!
Down! Down! Now, now!
Down! Down! Down!
Oompa has been shot!
Down!
He is not breathing!
Do not die. Come on! Man!
Do not die. Please
do not die.
Oompa! Stay alive, Oompa!
We cannot stay here.
They will be back.
That alleyway. We will
have cover there.
No! It is too far.
If we are out in the open that long,
they will pick us, one by one.
We need a distraction.
- Okay.
- Okay! What?
I will distract them.
When I tell you to run.
Run as fast as you can.
- Cover me, now!
- What?
Listen up!
On my go, haul ass
to the alleyway.
Back out there! Are you crazy?
Listen, Teacup, you just
got to trust me. Okay!
You are going to run and
do not look back.
- What about Oompa?
- He is dead, man. We have to leave him.
Sorry, man! I am sorry.
- Zombie, now! Run!
- Haul ass!
- Go! Go! Go!
- Let us move! Move! Move!
- Stairs.
- I get it.
Clear!
Are we still alive?
I think so.
Watch out!
Do not shoot! It is Ringer!
That was badass, Ringer.
I would hug you, if I did not think you
will punch me in the nuts for this.
Okay! So, what do we do now?
None of this makes sense.
They knock down planes out of
the sky, and cause earthquakes.
However, are they afraid
of an army of children?
There is something Vouch
is not telling us.
Okay! I am not risking
my life for this.
Ringer, what are you doing?
I am not enlisting.
I am better out
there on my own.
You know what is best for
you. You will do the same.
- Holy shit! What is this?
- Zombie, you see this.
- She is green!
- What have you people?
Put your guns down.
You are one of them!
You are an alien!
What about are you talking?
I just saved your asses!
If she is one of them,
we have to take her out now.
Pound cake, just calm
down. All right!
- We have...
- I can see it!
I can see it inside of her!
- There is nothing inside me!
- Shut up!
- Zombie, what do we do? Do we shoot her?
- It is your call, Zombie.
Zombie, what are you doing?
What is up, man?
- My God! What is going on, man?
- Come on!
Hey! Put your guns down.
Put your guns down.
Do not shoot. Calm down. She is
not a "The Others". Neither I am.
- I am glowing green, right.
- Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah, listen.
You know me.
Come on, Dumbo. You
know who I am.
Put the guns down.
Just put them down!
I am not a "The Others".
I do not think even any of those people out
there shooting at us are "The Others".
Reznik, Vosch...
They lied to us.
They laid to us, man.
Green does not mean alien.
Green means human.
Just, without one of these.
What about are you talking?
Do not people see?
Those lenses, these trackers,
it is all fake, man.
It is an illusion.
It is a trick.
They were not testing these.
They were testing us.
They were seeing how we would do,
how we would hold under pressure.
All right! If we would do
what we were trained to do.
- To kill "The Others"!
- No, to kill the survivors, man!
To kill survivors.
Yeah, well, what about the people outside,
the ones that were shooting at us?
They are human.
Why would the Army want
us to kill other humans?
Because the Army,
Reznik, Vosch...
They are "The Others".
In addition, because
we are kids.
They thought could manipulate
us to do their dirty work.
We are not fighting
the fifth Wave.
We are the fifth Wave.
God!
So...
What do we do?
Take out your trackers.
We go away off.
This means we cannot go back.
You know that, right!
Nugget.
I left him back at the base.
- I was trying to protect him.
- Jesus!
- I have to go back.
- That is suicide, dude.
- No, man! I have to go back.
- You cannot wander back in there.
- They will know.
- I cannot leave him there!
I will put in back the
tracker. They will pick up me.
You go ahead.
I will meet with you later.
Dumbo, where can I take a bullet
in the torso and not die?
- Are you serious?
- I am not kidding, man.
Where can I take a bullet in the
torso? I have to make it look real.
It is the only way,
I am getting back alive.
It is impossible, man.
There are too many organs.
There is to be in
somewhere, man!
Ringer! She can shoot in me.
All right! I know she can.
Do you want me
to shoot in you?
Do not pretend like you
have not thought about this.
Where do you want
me to shoot him?
I mean, the... Shit!
Evan Walker?
You are out of your
drone sector.
Hey!
Put the gun down. Stay away.
Cassie, run!
Where is my gun?
Evan?
Drop the gun.
Evan, drop it.
If I was going to kill you, Cassie, I
would have done it a long time ago.
Who are you?
You are one of them. You are
a fucking "The Others".
I am human.
However, I am "The
Others", too.
I am both.
This is not the first time
"The Others" have been here.
They came before and created
sleeper agents, like me.
I always felt different.
Growing up, there was
this voice in my head.
It was quiet, but
it was there.
In addition, when
the ship arrived,
it was like a switch
flip inside me,
and the sleeper woke up.
How many people
have you killed?
Did you kill your family?
No.
The disease...
The disease that "The Others" created.
The disease that you created.
Your family loved you.
Our kind believe
that love is just a trick.
An instinct.
A way to protect
your genetic future.
Do you really believe that?
I did.
Then I saw you.
I do not know how.
I do not understand it, but...
It was as you flip
the switch back.
You made me want to
be human again.
Did you shoot me?
No.
I saved you.
I was wrong.
They are wrong.
Love is not a trick.
It is real.
I know, now because of you.
Look! Stay back!
I do not want to
hear you anymore.
Just stay.
Cassie, please, just
let me help you.
All I want to do is
help you to find Sam.
Get on your knees, Evan.
Come on! Get on your knees.
Listen!
The Army is controlled
by "The Others".
They are preparing the kids.
For what?
To kill the last humans.
They will search you.
You cannot be armed.
If you follow me.
I will shoot in you.
Soldier, where is your unit?
All dead!
What is your number?
Two-nine-five!
Two-nine-five. He will live.
Let us bug out!
All right! Copy
that, Tango Three.
Tango Three returning to base!
Two-nine-five on deck!
The rest of the squad
are reported KIA.
Is it all right? It is
all right. We got you.
Five-four-seven!
Any family do not
know that you be dead?
No, just me.
Stand up.
Do you know why you
are here, Cassie?
To get revenge.
He is a "The Others".
I know.
It is impossible to tell.
Look through here.
This is its true form.
It is hiding that face.
What happened out there?
It was bad, sir.
We surrounded.
We tried to move to cover,
however, as soon as that we did...
They were everywhere, sir.
- Everyone has hit.
- Except you.
I took a bullet, sir.
However, you survived.
It is a miracle,
the way that bullet went right
through you and managed.
However, everything
is important.
Let us make a deal.
You dropped your lie,
in addition, I will drop mine.
Tell me, Ben.
What do you know?
I know what you are.
You are going to kill
me, are not you?
Yes.
Why?
What is the point
of any of this?
- What did we do to deserve...
- Nothing.
"The Others" occupied
the space we need.
We are not different, Ben. Your kind
would do exactly the same thing.
No.
Our kind would not wiped
out an entire species.
Of course! You would.
You have been doing
it for centuries.
Sir, Sergeant Reznik is dead.
Security found her body.
- Where?
- In medical.
There is more, three guards
were killed at the west gate.
What, the hell, was that?
An explosion, sir. It came
from inside the base.
- Get rid of him.
- Damage to Sector Three!
- Captain.
- Let us go.
We need to move all the recruits off the
base. Get them on planes to Wonderland, now.
Deploy units. Find out
who is attacking us.
South corridor! On the double!
They are taking out our
security cameras.
Bring the drones home so we
can see who is attacking us.
Yeah! These are the changes
from about 60 minutes ago.
Hey!
- Do not move, all right! Do not move!
- It is okay! Okay, all right!
Cassie? My name is Ben Parish. We
used to go to high school together.
I know who you are.
What squad are you?
I am looking for
my brother, Sammy.
Sammy?
Sammy Sullivan?
- Do you know my brother?
- Yes, yes, we are in the same squad.
- Do you know where he is?
- I am trying to get to him right now.
All recruits report to
the transport area.
They are sending the
kids to war.
Vosch. The Army.
They are "The Others".
Look! Sammy is about to
get on one of those planes.
If we do not go now, you are not going
to see him again. Do you understand?
We do not have so much time.
- All recruits report to the transport area.
- All right!
- Do you ready?
- Come on!
Once the recruits reach Wonderland, get
they ready for immediate deployment.
Yes, sir.
Transfer area is this way.
Hey!
This is a restricted area.
- Hey! It is all right.
- On your knees!
Hands behind your head!
No! He is fine. He is
one of us. It is okay.
Evan, what are you doing here?
Helping you.
Who is he?
Ben Parish.
Ben Parish?
Yeah.
He was just here.
I told to you not follow me.
Well, I decided to ignore you.
I have been planting bombs.
In about ten minutes, when the
last plane full of kids takes off.
I am taking this place
down, for good.
I am sorry I lie
to you, Cassie.
I was wrong, when I said I was
both one of you and one of them.
You cannot be both.
You have to choose.
I choose you.
Go!
Get out of here.
I will find you.
- Who was that?
- Evan Walker.
We have to go to find Sammy.
I think Evan Walker is about
to blow this place up.
Next floor up.
Go ahead to the northeast
corridor, number 22, now!
Which way?
This way.
Stay with your group leader.
Proceed to the transport vehicles
in a calm and orderly fashion.
Stay with your group leader.
Proceed to the
transport vehicles.
Come on, move along, people.
Straight ahead.
- Stay with your group leader.
- Keep moving.
- Do not fall behind, everyone.
- Where are they going?
Once you are on the plane, will
receive further instructions.
Keep moving.
Straight ahead.
Stay with your group leader.
What is her problem?
Sammy? Sammy?
Sammy! Sammy! Sammy!
My God! My God!
Hi.
- Cassie!
- Do not!
We have to go. All right!
Let us go.
Once you are on the plane, you
will receive further instructions.
Come on.
Hi!
I missed you so much, Sammy.
I missed you, Cassie.
Look! What I brought
back for you.
It is Bear.
I love you.
I love you too, Sammy.
Hey.
I have to take
out his tracker.
All right! It is not
going to hurt. Okay!
Is it back up?
Are all the
recruits accounted?
Yes, sir. Six barracks left.
Good.
Power up my bird. Last plane is
in the air, evacuate the base.
Come on!
Shit! It is Vosch!
Run! Run! Go to the truck!
Go!
Sammy, run faster!
Go! Go!
Come on, Sammy!
- Run!
- Cassie!
Shit!
Who is that?
- Come on!
- Come on! Get in!
Come on!
- Quick, Sammy. Get in!
- All right, come on! Get in! Get in!
Drive!
Thanks for coming back.
- Do you feel better?
- Yeah, thanks, Dumbo.
Make sure to give
her food first.
Let me know if it starts
hurting or anything like that.
- Okay.
- All right.
Teacup, how are you feeling?
Pretty good.
All right.
How much longer for food?
I do not know. Not long.
What are you looking?
Trying to find the stars.
It is a little
early, is not it?
You named after
a star, right?
Cassiopeia.
Yeah. A cluster of stars.
I named after
Ben and Jerry's.
The truth.
Nothing made my dad
happier than ice cream.
I am sure you made
him happier.
Yeah.
So...
What will we do now?
We have to save
those other kids.
Yeah.
How are we going to do that?
Dinner is ready.
I do not know yet.
Well...
Let us worry about that tomorrow,
in addition, get something to eat.
All right.
Hey, Sammy.
Wake up, friend.
Hey, there he is.
Come on.
Come on, lazy bones.
Put your bear down, could you?
"The Others" see our
hope as a weakness.
As a delusion.
But, they are wrong.
It is our hope that
let us survive.
That lets us bend,
but remains unbroken.
- Do you two know each other?
- Yeah, we went to high school together.
It is our hope that will
let us win one day.
It is our hope that
makes us human.
THE FIFTH WAVE
Translation. Review. Synchronization by Angel.